

# **AKIS GAZEPIDIS**

DATA SCIENTIST

## **PROFILE**

Data Scientist with experience in information extraction techniques used on do cuments, scraping data through internet and training of machine learning models. My passion is to accelerate internal company processes and lead to data-driven decisions.

### CONTACT

6986777430



<u>akisgazepidis@gmail.com</u>



in <u>linkedin.com/in/akisgazepidis</u>



<u>akisgazepidis.github.io/Akis\_Gazepidis</u>



Peristeri, Athens, 12137, Greece

## HARD SKILLS

- Python
- Snowflake
- Azure Devops
- PostgreSQL
- Azure SQL server
- PowerBi
- Git
- Postman
- Docker
- CI/CD
- MongoDB

### EXPERIENCE

### **DATA ENGINEERING CONSULTANT**

### **D-ONE**

Apr 2023- Present

- · Build, test and deploy Snowflake tables.
- · Interact with Rest APIs and create collections.
- Provide insights to users through PowerBi reports.

Project: Database Integration project from Azure SQL server databases to one unified Snowflake database.

### **DATA SCIENTIST**

### <u>Generali</u>

Jan 2022- Apr 2023

- Integrate Bitbucket version control system in development.
- · Consolidate data with the use of APIs.
- Create RPA bots so as to automate consuming processes.
- · Integrate OCR, Machine Vision & Machine Learning fields to RPA bots.

### **DATA SCIENTIST**

### Purposeful

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Collect publication patents through Google's BigQuery.
- Analyze texts with Natural Language Process (NLP).
- Conduct topic modeling analysis using Latent Dirichlet Allocation. (LDA)

## SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Team Working

## LANGUAGES

Greek - Native

English - ILTES 6.5

### PORTFOLIO

Optimization of Titan's Mill

<u>Deep Learning - loan prediction</u>

Classcentral scraper

**Image Handwritting Recognition** 

NLP - Climate Change IR System

#### JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Big Blue Data Academy

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- · Web scraping with Beautiful Soup, Requests & Selenium.
- Consolidate various data sources using Pandas & JSON.
- · Data visualization using Plotly, Dash, Power BI.
- Recommendation System with Natural Language Process (NLP) & TFIDF

### EDUCATION

#### **WORKSHOPS - CERTIFICATIONS**

**D-ONE** - BigQuery Essentials - Nov 2023

Microsoft - Data Analyst Associate - Aug 2023

### **MASTER OF SCIENCE**

American College of Greece - Data Science

2022 - Present

### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

**University of Piraeus - Statistics & Insurance** 

2011 - 2020

### DATA SCIENCE BOOTCAMP 500 HOURS HANDS-ON

Big Blue Data Academy

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Databases (SQL, MongoDB), APIs & Web Scraping
- EDA & Data Cleaning (Pandas, Numpy, Regex)
- Big Data (PySpark) & Cloud Computing (Amazon Web Services)
- Machine Learning (Scikit Learn) & Deep Learning (Keras)
- · Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Dash, PowerBi)
- Communication & Presentation skills

# DATA SCIENCE ACADEMY 100 HOURS HANDS-ON

Regeneration Academy by TITAN - Code. Hub

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021